teachingchannel.org 2016-11-28

# Teaching Channel Respects the Privacy of Teachers, Administrators and All Visitors

**Last Updated September 8, 2015**

## Teaching Channel values the privacy of our users and visitors.

At Teaching Channel, we understand that you value your privacy, and we want to help make your use of our Site (defined below) and services, including our content offerings through third-party sites such as Facebook, YouTube, and our newsletters and blogs (together with the Site, referred to in this policy collectively as our " **Service** " or " **Services** ") a satisfying experience. This policy (the “ **Privacy Policy** ”) describes the information we collect on www.teachingchannel.org, including personally identifiable information, in connection with our Services, and explains how we use and disclose this information. By accessing and/or using our website, currently located at [www.teachingchannel.org](https://www.teachingchannel.org/) (the “Site”), you agree to be bound by the provisions of this Privacy Policy.

Please note that this Privacy Policy is incorporated into, and made a part of, the Teaching Channel Terms and Conditions (the " **Terms** "). Capitalized terms used and not defined in this policy have the meaning given to them in the Terms.

### What We Collect

It's our policy to create website content that limits the need for collection of information from our visitors. However, there are various ways you may submit, and we may collect, information.

> #### User-Provided Information
> 
> You may provide to Teaching Channel what is generally called "personally identifiable" information (such as your name, e-mail address, postal mailing address, home/mobile telephone number or demographic information, billing and/or payment information) when communicating with Teaching Channel or using our Services. Such communication may occur when you register for the Site, request or transmit teaching materials, participate in blogs or discussion groups, take part in our online polls, comment on postings, videos, or our other content offerings, provide your information in submission form provided by Teaching Channel, subscribe to or purchase premium content or services, or otherwise request further communications from Teaching Channel.
> 
> #### "Cookies" Information
> 
> Technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags, and scripts are used by Teaching Channel and our partners such as marketing partners, advertisers, affiliates, or analytics or service providers. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the Site, to serve ads based on a user’s prior visits to the Site and other sites on the Internet, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis.

Google and others, as third party vendors, use cookies to serve ads on our Site. Google’s use of the DoubleClick cookie enables it and its partners to serve ads to our users based on their visit to our Site or other sites on the Internet. You may opt out of the use of the DoubleClick Cookie for interest-based advertising by visiting the [Google Ads Settings page](https://www.google.com/settings/u/0/ads/authenticated). You can also visit the Consumer Choice Page at [www.aboutads.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/) to see your opt out choices from receiving interest-based advertising from some or all participating companies.

We use cookies to remember users’ settings for authentication. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some features or areas of our site may be limited.

> #### "Ad Choices/Opting out
> 
> Other third-party ad serving companies or networks may display ads on the Site. You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers or ad networks for more information on their practices and for instructions on how to opt-out of certain practices. This Privacy Policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the tracking technologies and activities of, those other advertisers, third-party advertising networks, or third-party advertising servers. For more information about third-party advertising networks and similar entities that use these technologies, see <http://www.aboutads.info/consumers>, and to opt-out of such ad networks' and services' advertising practices, go to the [Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/), the [Digital Advertising Alliance opt-out page](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/), or the [Your Online Choices](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/uk/your-ad-choices) page.
> 
> #### "Automatically Collected" Information
> 
> As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. We do not link this automatically collected data to other information we collect about you.

We may combine this automatically collected log information with other information we collect about you. We do this to improve services we offer you, to improve marketing, analytics, or site functionality.

> #### Flash LSOs (HTML5 / Flash LSOs)
> 
> We use local storage objects (LSOs) such as HTML5 or Flash to store content information and preferences. Third Parties, with whom we partner to provide certain features on our site, or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity, use LSOs such as HTML5 to collect and store information.

Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5 LSOs. To manage Flash LSOs please click [here](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html).

> Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5 LSOs. To manage Flash LSOs please click here: <http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html>.
> 
> #### Information from Other Sources
> 
> We may also obtain information, including personally identifiable information, from third parties and sources other than our Site or Services, such as advertisers, marketers and analytic data collection services. If we combine or associate information from other sources with personally identifiable information that we collect through our Site or Services, we will treat the combined information as personally identifiable information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

### The Way We Use Information

We use all the information you provide, or that we collect or receive, in a variety of ways in connection with the operation of the Site and the Service. For example:

> Teaching Channel uses the information you provide or that we collect to develop, operate, maintain, enhance, and provide all of the features and services found on our Site or Services now and in the future. We will use your email address to contact you for administrative purposes, for customer service purposes, to address intellectual property infringement, rights of privacy, or defamation issues, or regarding User Postings that you have submitted to us.
> 
> Teaching Channel uses the information that you provide or that we collect to understand and analyze the usage trends and preferences of our users, to improve the way our Services works and looks, and to create new features and functionality.
> 
> Teaching Channel may use "automatically collected" information and "cookies" information, alone or in combination with other information we have collected from you, to streamline and facilitate our provision of the Services, such as to: (a) personalize our services, such as remembering your information so that you will not have to re-enter it during your visit or the next time you use our Service; (b) provide customized third party advertisements, content, and information; (c) monitor and analyze the effectiveness of our Services and third party marketing activities; (d) monitor aggregate site usage metrics, track movements around the Site and analyze trends and demographic information; and (e) track your entries, submissions, and status in any promotions or other activities.
> 
> Teaching Channel may use your email address or other personally identifiable information to communicate with you in a variety of ways, such as by sending you (i) messages about our Services, such as when you receive communications from another user, (ii) promotional messages about our Services or third-party products you may be interested in, and (iii) communications on behalf of other users who think you may be interested in our Services or certain content available on the Site. Generally, you have the ability to opt-out of receiving any such communications, either through links provided in the messages, or by contacting us at [privacy@teachingchannel.org](mailto:privacy@teachingchannel.org).

We partner with a third party ad network to either display advertising on our Site or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our ad network partner uses cookies and Web beacons to collect non-personally identifiable information about your activities on this and other Web sites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/). Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads.

### Updating/Accessing/Amending/Correcting Personally Identifiable Information

If your personally identifiable information changes, you should correct, update, amend, or deactivate it by making the change on our member information page or by emailing our Customer Support at privacy@teachingchannel.org, or by contacting us by telephone or postal mail at the contact information listed below.

If you wish to subscribe to our newsletter(s), we will use your name and email address to send the newsletter to you. Out of respect for your privacy, you may choose to stop receiving our newsletter or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails, accessing the email preferences in your account settings page, or you can contact us at privacy@teachingchannel.org.

### Surveys or Contests

From time-to-time we may provide you the opportunity to participate in contests, sweepstakes or surveys on the site which require you to disclose certain personally identifiable information in order to participate. Participation in these surveys or contests is completely voluntary and you therefore have a choice whether or not to disclose this information. The requested information typically includes contact information (such as name and shipping address), and demographic information (such as zip code).

### How We Disclose Information

We may disclose your personally identifiable information to third parties in a variety of circumstances in connection with developing and providing our Services and operating our business. For example:

> Our Site enables users to communicate in a variety of ways. Any personally identifiable information that you voluntarily choose to include in a publicly accessible area on our Services, such as in a blog discussion, user review or other User Submission, will be publicly available to others. This also applies to information you choose to make available through our features that connect to third party services, such as Twitter and Facebook. Teaching Channel may also syndicate content posted in public areas to other third party services. Once you make your personally identifiable information publicly available and accessible, that information may be collected and used by others without restriction. Similarly, information you make available to another user or users through private or semi-private communication channel may be collected and used by the recipients without restriction.
> 
> Teaching Channel discloses automatically collected and other aggregate non-personally-identifiable information with interested third parties to assist such parties in understanding the usage, viewing, and demographic patterns for certain programs, content, services, advertisements, promotions, and/or functionality on our Services.
> 
> Teaching Channel works with third party service providers to provide website hosting and maintenance as well as other services, such as sweepstakes administration. To the extent it is necessary for these service providers to complete their contractual obligations to Teaching Channel, these third parties may have access to or process your personally identifiable information. Generally, these disclosures are made under terms comparable to this policy, and the recipients are limited to using the information for the purpose for which it was provided. For example, Teaching Channel may provide your payment information (and supporting personally identifiable information) to a third party payment processor in connection with processing your payments for subscription fees.
> 
> Teaching Channel may also disclose your information if required to do so by law, where we believe that such action is necessary to comply with state or federal laws (such as U.S. Copyright law), in response to a court order, judicial or other government subpoena or warrant, or to otherwise cooperate with law enforcement activity.
> 
> Teaching Channel also reserves the right to disclose your information that we believe, in our sole discretion, is appropriate or useful to protect you, other users, third parties, or ourselves from harm or liability; to protect Teaching Channel and others from fraudulent, abusive, or unlawful uses or activity; to investigate and defend ourselves against any third party claims or allegations; to assist government and law enforcement agencies; to protect the security or integrity of our Services; or to protect the rights, property, or personal safety of Teaching Channel, our users, or others. We may also disclose your personally identifiable information to any other third party with your prior consent to do so.

### Tell-A-Friend

If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our Services, share a video or other aspect of the Services, we will ask you for your friend's name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the Site. Teaching Channel stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email and tracking the success of our referral program.

Your friend may contact us at privacy@teachingchannel.org to request that we remove this information from our database.

### Import Contacts

You can import contacts from your Outlook or other email account address book to invite them to become members of our Site. We collect the username and password for the email account you wish to import your contacts from and will only use it for that purpose.

### Links

Our Site contains links to websites and services provided by third parties. Any personally identifiable information you provide on third party sites or services is provided directly to that third party and is subject to that third party's policies, if any, governing privacy and security. We are not responsible for the content or privacy and security practices and policies of third party sites or services to which links are displayed on the Service. We encourage you to learn about third parties' privacy and security policies before providing them with personally identifiable information.

**Social Media Widgets**  
Our Services include Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

**Single Sign-On**  
You can log in to our Site using sign-in services such as Facebook Connect or an Open ID provider. These services will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personally identifiable information with us such as your name and email address to pre-populate our sign up form. Services like Facebook Connect give you the option to post information about your activities on the Site to your profile page to share with others within your network.

### Blog / Forum

Our Site offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personally identifiable information from our blog or community forum, contact us at [privacy@teachingchannel.org](mailto:privacy@teachingchannel.org). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personally identifiable information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

### Testimonials

We display personal testimonials of satisfied customers on our Site in addition to other endorsements. With your consent, we may post your testimonial along with your name. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at [privacy@teachingchannel.org](mailto:privacy@teachingchannel.org).

### Our Commitment to Children's Privacy

Protecting the privacy of young children is especially important. For that reason, Teaching Channel does not knowingly collect or maintain personally identifiable information from persons under 13 years of age. **IF YOU ARE NOT 13 YEARS-OF-AGE OR OLDER YOU ARE NOT ALLOWED TO USE THE SITE OR SUBMIT PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION TO TEACHING CHANNEL.** If Teaching Channel learns that personally identifiable information of persons less than 13-years-of-age has been collected through our Service, then Teaching Channel will take the appropriate steps to delete this information. If you are a parent or guardian and discover that your child under the age of 13 has posted, submitted or otherwise communicated personally identifiable information to our Service without your consent, then you may alert Teaching Channel at [privacy@teachingchannel.org](mailto:privacy@teachingchannel.org) so that we may take appropriate action to remove the child's personally identifiable information from our systems.

### Our Commitment to Data Security

Teaching Channel uses certain industry standard managerial and technical safeguards to increase the integrity and security of personally identifiable information stored on our systems. When you enter sensitive information (such as a credit card number) on our order forms, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). We cannot, however, ensure or warrant the security of any information transmitted to Teaching Channel, nor can we guarantee that such information may not be accessed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by a breach, circumvention, failure, or interruption of any of our physical, technical, or managerial safeguards.

If Teaching Channel learns of a security systems breach, then we may attempt to notify you electronically so that you can take appropriate protective steps. We may post a notice through our Site if a security breach occurs. Depending on where you live, you may have a legal right to receive notice of a security breach in writing. To receive a free written notice of a security breach you should notify us at [privacy@teachingchannel.org](mailto:privacy@teachingchannel.org).

### International Visitors

Our Sites are intended solely for visitors located within the United States. If you nonetheless choose to use our Site from the European Union or other regions of the world with laws governing data collection and use that may differ from U.S. law, then please note that you are transferring your personally identifiable information outside of those regions to the United States for storage and processing and by providing your personally identifiable information on the Site you consent to that transfer, storage, and processing. Further, we may transfer this data from the United States to other jurisdictions in connection with storing and processing data, fulfilling your requests, and operating our Sites.

### Data Retention

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services, contact us at privacy@teachingchannel.org. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

### In the Event of Merger or Sale

In the event that all or a portion of Teaching Channel or its assets are acquired by or merged with a third party entity, we reserve the right, in any of these circumstances, to transfer or assign the information that we have collected from users in connection with such merger, acquisition, sale, or other change of control. You will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Site of any change in ownership or uses of your personally identifiable information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information.

### Changes and Updates to this Privacy Policy

Please revisit this page periodically to stay aware of any changes to this Privacy Policy, which may be revised periodically at our sole discretion. If we modify the Privacy Policy, we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account), or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. In the event that the modifications materially alter your rights or obligations hereunder, we will make reasonable efforts to notify you of the change. For example, we may send a message to your email address, if we have one on file, or generate a pop-up or similar notification when you access our Site for the first time after such material changes are made. Our amended Privacy Policy will automatically take effect five (5) days after it is made available through our Site. If you do not agree with any changes to the Privacy Policy, you must terminate your account and cease use of our Services. Your continued use of our Services after the revised Privacy Policy has become effective indicates that you have read, understood, and agreed to the current version of the Privacy Policy.

### Your Choices

You may, of course, decline to share certain personally identifiable information with Teaching Channel, in which case Teaching Channel may not be able to provide to you some or all of the features and functionality found on our Site. Please understand that Teaching Channel may retain all information you have submitted for a variety of purposes, including backups and archiving, prevention of fraud and abuse, analytics and the use and disclosure purposes described herein.

### Contacting Us

If you have questions about this Privacy Policy, or our Services, please contact:

**Teaching Channel**  
901 Mission Street, Suite 105  
San Francisco, CA 94103
